skyward.com 2019-08-25

# Privacy Policy - Skyward

**Who We Are:** Skyward, Inc. ("Skyward") provides enterprise data management solutions to our customers. The privacy of our customers and other individuals who visit our websites is very important to us.  We have created this Privacy Policy to help you better understand how we handle your personal information and to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy.  The data controller of Skyward’s websites is: Skyward, Inc., 2601 Skyward Drive, Stevens Point, WI 54482.  Skyward’s data protection officer is: Jeff Ramlow ([content@skyward.com](mailto:content@skyward.com)).

  **When This Privacy Policy Applies:** This Privacy Policy applies to the web pages at [https://www.skyward.com](https://www.skyward.com/).  This Privacy Policy does not apply to any offline data collection practices, to the data collection practices of any Skyward customers, or any entities affiliated with Skyward. This Privacy Policy also does not apply to any third-party websites, services, applications, or online resources to which this website may link, frame, or otherwise reference. Skyward takes no responsibility for the content or privacy practices of those third parties. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any third party website you access. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [content@skyward.com](mailto:content@skyward.com).

  **U.S. Privacy Shield:**   Skyward participates in the EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Principles as set forth by the US Department of Commerce. Skyward is committed to applying the Privacy Shield Principles to all personal data it receives. More information on the Privacy Shield and the Privacy Shield List can be found at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>. Skyward is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives under the Privacy Shield Framework. Skyward complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield, Skyward is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  If you have an unresolved privacy concern related to personal data processed or transferred by Skyward pursuant to the Privacy Shield that Skyward has not addressed to your satisfaction, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider at no cost here: <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>. Under certain circumstances, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

  **Information That We Collect:** As a general principle, any personal information you provide to Skyward through the websites is entirely voluntary.  In order to access certain portions of the websites and other Skyward offerings such as registering for events, seminars, forums, blogs, and networks (such as the Skyward Community), you may be asked to create a user profile that contains certain personal information.  User profiles provide the option to display personal information about you to other users, including but not limited to your name, photo, social media accounts, postal or email address, telephone number, personal interests, skills, and other basic information.  You may choose not to provide such information.  However, in many cases, if you elect not to provide information to Skyward, it will not be able to process certain requests, such as signing up for a newsletter, registering for an event or accessing certain other networks linked to the websites.

  **Cookies:**   Skyward may use cookies to collect technical information and aggregate non-personal information regarding preferences, website traffic, and other similar types of information to assist Skyward in improving the websites and the products and services that it offers to its customers.  Skyward does not honor “Do not track” requests and Skyward does not track its users.  However, you may elect not to accept cookies by changing the designated settings on your web browser.  However, if you elect not to accept cookies, you may not be able to use certain functions and features of the websites.

  **Information Storage And Retention:**   Skyward will retain your personal information: (i) for as long as needed to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected; (ii) until you withdraw your consent; or (ii) as necessary to comply with Skyward’s legal obligations. Skyward stores the personal information you provide on servers located in the United States. 

  **Your Choices:**   You can manage your communication preferences by following the instructions in each promotion email from us to unsubscribe or by sending us a message to [content@skyward.com](mailto:content@skyward.com). These choices do not apply to service notifications or other required communications that are considered part of Skyward’s services to its customers, which you may receive periodically unless you stop using or cancel our services.  At any time, you have the right to access or correct your personal information or completely terminate your account by contacting Skyward at [content@skyward.com](mailto:content@skyward.com).  If you choose to terminate your account, your personal information will be deleted. However, any public activity on your account prior to deletion will remain stored on our servers and will remain accessible to the public.

  **Disclosure of Information:**   Except as provided below, Skyward will not disclose to third parties personal information you provide without your prior consent.  Skyward may disclosure your personal information to third parties who assist Skyward in providing the services for which the information was provided, provided such third parties have agreed to maintain the confidentiality of such information.  Skyward may also disclosure your personal information if it has a good faith belief that the law requires such disclosure.

  **Data Security:** Skyward protects the confidentiality of the personal information, collected by Skyward. To secure the information collected online, prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure only appropriate use of information that is collected, Skyward has implemented appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures consistent with industry standards. Further, Skyward requires that employees keep personal information confidential. Skyward cautions its customers and website visitors that no medium of communication, including the Internet, is entirely secure.

  **Children's Privacy:** Skyward does not intend for the websites to be used by anyone under the age of 13 and does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 without appropriate parental or guardian consent.

  **Notification of Changes:** Skyward’s policies and procedures for handling customer information have been created with the understanding that Internet technologies are still evolving and that Internet business methods are continuing to evolve to meet the needs and opportunities of the changing technologies. As a result, Skyward reserves the right to modify its policies and procedures at any time, so please review it frequently. If we decide to change this privacy statement in any material way, we will notify you by amending the "Last Updated" date at the top of this page. We may also notify you by other means prior to the changes taking effect, such as by posting a notice on the websites or sending you a notification. By continuing to use the websites after such revisions are in effect, you accept and agree to the revisions.
